

Sara Malvar, PhD

- malvar.sara@gmail.com
- Rua Poetisa Colombina, 141 apt 101, São Paulo
- github.com/smalvar

- (61) 98115-6756
- in linkedin.com/in/saramalvar

PROFILE

Electrical engineer with 6+ years of experience in data analysis and machine learning. Certified professional with university teaching and distance learning experience, predictive analysis for business and data mining. I have more than 12 publications in international conferences and journals. Worked as a consultant for large companies such as FastShop, Shell, Symrise and acts as a reviewer and mentor at Udacity, in addition to producing Machine Learning courses for Alura and mentoring Awari Data Science students.

LANGUAGES

English	••••
Spanish	••••
Japanese	• • • •
Portuguese	••••

SKILLS

Python	• • • •
Keras/Tensorflow	• • • •
KPI Dashboards	• • • •
Tableau	• • • •
Alteryx	• • • •
Data mining	• • • •

EXPERIENCE

- IBM Field Technical Sales Specialist 2011 2014
- Vert TIC Electrica Engineer 2014 - 2014
- University of Brasilia Professor
- University UDF Professor 2014 - 2015
- Udacity Mentor e reviewer
 2018 NOW
- Alura Machine Learning instructor
 2019 NOW
- Awari Machine Learning Mentor 2019 - NOW

FORMAÇÃO

University of Brasilia

2009 - 2014

B.A. Electrical Engineering

University of Brasilia

2014 - 2015

MS.c. Mechanical Science

University of Sao Paulo / University of Pennsylvania

2016 - 2019

PhD Mechanica Engineering

University of Sao Paulo

2019 - NOW

Postdoctorate Fellow Engineering

AWARDS

- Best undergraduation project (ABCM/EMBRAER)
- Best master dissertation (ABCM/EMBRAER)
- FAMELAB finalist Scientific Communication Prize (2017)
- FAMELAB semifinalist Scientific Communication Prize (2020)